# Sadisha Galappatti

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · CSM, SECURITY ENTHUSIAST

□ (+1) 289-339-2717 | Sadishag@gmail.com | # www.sadishagalappatti.ca | • sadishag | • sadishag

#### Summary\_

Software Engineer in Training currently working at Manulife in a Product Development capacity. 2+ years of work experience with backend/infrastructure, web development and security and experience being a tech lead in a small team. I know my way around a unix like terminal and love to build out my perfect development environment. The hard challenges keep me motivated and moving forward. Constantly on the search for opportunities to grow personally and professionally.

SKILLS: Python, Java, NodeJS, React, Angular, Ansible, Bash, HTML/CSS, Golang, Ruby on Rails, C/C++, C#, MySQL, Redis, Cassandra, Postgres, Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana, Apigee, PCF, Kubernetes

#### Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Manulife Toronto, Canada

ASSOCIATE FULL STACK ENGINEER

July 2019 - Present

- Design and develop product line in Individual Insurance for Insurance Advisors and customers
- Implementing micro-service architecture in Nodejs with front end built with React
- Deployed to PaaS infrastructure on PCF including initial steps to push to Kubernetes cluster on Azure
- · Pipelines implemented using Jenkins, Concourse with code analysis, scanning using Sonarqube
- · Contributing to QA/QE automation by developing Cucumber tests implemented using the TestNG framework and Selenium

RBCx Toronto, Canada

**RBCx Season 5 Participant** 

Feb 2019 - April 2019

- 9 week immersive business challenge implementing the frameworks of Design Thinking to distil a problem and design a solution
- Committed to a solution that would solve the crowding problem on transit users commute by crowd sourcing user locations and determining capacity on specific vehicles
- Started building the solution back end using AWS(DynamoDB, Lambda, SQS, EC2), Go, Python
- Pitched the solution to an audience of 300+ RBC employees and partners at RBCxpo (expo showcasing all the solutions)
- · Won Best Pitch award as voted by the audience

RBC Toronto, Canada

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | TECHNICAL LEAD

June 2017 - July 2019

- Architected and deployed the API Gateway platform within a time period of 4 months (https://developer.rbc.com)
- Ensured full scalability and security of the platform during implementation and automated operational/CI/CD tasks using Ansible, Jenkins, Python and Github
- Increased turnaround time to engage and integrate external partnerships for the entire bank by 50%
- Reduced number of rollbacks by implementing efficient, automated deployment processes
- · Managed engagement, education and onboarding to the API Platform and developed standards around usage
- Managed and maintained the infrastructure to run the API Gateway platform to allow for a 99.999% up time SLA and lead the push for an in production zero downtime upgrade of the platform
- Enabled Oauth and Mutual Authenticaion (2waySSL) as generic policy to add to API's. Policies are now used in 300+ API's at RBC
- Developed a CI/CD process to push compiled Angular build artifacts to PCF using Jenkins and NodeJS
- Contributor to various internal open-source (innersource) projects at RBC
- KEY ACHIEVEMENTS: RBC Digital Q3 2018 Team Award, Top Performance Rating for 2 years in a row

Blackberry Limited Waterloo, Canada

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

Sept. 2015 - Aug. 2016

- Built restful API's (Ruby on Rails) following a microservice architecture as part of a 2.0 deployment of BlackBerry CloudConsole application
- · Dashboard development such as chargeback data pull, OS level patch monitoring, KAFKA/GRAFANA integration
- Developed on top of an asset tracking configuration management platform

## **Program Committees**

2013 - Pres Technical/Youth Board Member, Wellwood Cancer Centre

Hamilton, Canada

### **Education**

McMaster University

Hamilton, Canada

B.Eng. in Software Engineering Class of 2017

FEBRUARY 23, 2020 SADISHA GALAPPATTI · RÉSUMÉ